Guide to the Acton Visual Materials at La Pietra MSS.LaPietra.001
Villa La Pietra
- Series III: Family Albums and Scrapbooks
  - Subseries B: Baby Books
    - Harold Acton, ca. 1904-1918; cuid287 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      His trip to America in 1906 (to Green Gables, Geneva Lake, and Chicago) is well recorded with prints of his relations Kathleen Sheriff, Clarence and Louise Mitchell, Rothwell Sheriff and Neath Stevens, Fritz Jewett, and the Cabin passenger list of the 'Kaiser Wilhelm II' September 18 1906.
      In 1906 he is photographed with Edward Neville at Villa La Pietra. In 1907 "mother was ill in America and Harold went to Mrs Labouchere's tree - Mrs Dodge's where he saw Father Xmas, to Lady Paget's and to Mrs McCalmont's at Villa Medici and his mother has had many complements on his behaviour and good manners." In February 1909 HA dressed as a Spanish bull fighter and WA as Pierrot went to Mrs Labouchere's fancy- dress ball. A clipping of 1911 describes a Christmas party for Anglo-American children given by Miss Penrose at the English School, mentioning Master Harold Acton, and numerous contemporaries including Master Bindon Blood, Berthe, Sebastiano and Francesca Braggiotti. There are prints of HA and WA in their costumes for the fancy-dress ball at the Braggiotti on 18th Feb 1912. There is a list in HA's hand of acceptances to a party he gave on 31 December 1913: "Iris Cutting, Marie-Lou Bourbon del Monte, Franca Antinori, [Elriyth] Arbuthnot, Nini, Mondo and Olga Robilon[t], three Fabbricotti, 5 Harach [or Harrach], 2 De Ritter, and 'Jackson baby'." An incomplete clipping [1914] reports that "Mr and Mrs Arthur Acton had a beautiful Christmas tree for children". A third clipping reports Lady Sybil Cutting's Cotillion for children at Villa Medici. With Master's (sic.) H. and WA Acton as Louis XV pages. Also present Miss Iris Cutting, S.na Rucellai, Signorina Bourbon del Monte, and others.
      Friends and relations of HA mentioned or photographed include: Mrs Hayden Bates, Mrs R.J. Crane, jr., Maud Buckingham, and his Mitchell relations, Auntie Stevens, Aunt Italia Blair (really his cousin), Aunt Mollie Blair, Aunt Marguerite, and Mrs John Mitchell (really his aunt) - these all shown in the list of gifts to baby Harold. Also Lady Enniskillen (who suggested it was good for him to 'creep' [crawl]), Cornelia and Isabelle O'Connor, and Mrs Brough (or Boyd).
      There is a print of Wixenford, Wokingham, HA's school, captioned 'Sept 1912: home from Xmas 1914-Easter 1915', and a postcard of Ashlawn, Benenden Kent 1917-18 (annotated on verso by HA 'I have made a mark with ink beside my dormitory window').
      Towards the end of the album are pressed flowers "from Grandfather's casket -Chicago, March 12th, 1916".
      The prints are sometimes duplicates of prints in I.C.1. (or sometimes prints of negatives in I.C.1.), but most of them are not duplicated elsewhere in the Collection. The annotations are all by HMA. The prints are pasted onto the pages.
    - William Acton, 1907-1917; cuid288 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      The album was printed in New York 1905 and is in good condition, a gift from WA's grandmother. The period covered is 1907-1917. 108 prints. Numerous prints include HMA and HA. There are prints of the gardens of Villa La Pietra (including the Vasche) and the interior of Villa La Pietra (the day nursery). It includes WA's first 'letters' and drawings, and is also a scrapbook.
      WA's birth at 2004 Calumet Avenue in Chicago is recorded on 16 August 1906, and his first few weeks in the US with a visit to his grandfather at Green Gables Lake Geneva, and the trip from New York on 18 September 1906 to Cherbourg (arriving 24th) and from there to Paris and by train to Firenze via Milano and Bologna.
      'Baby's Gifts' include "$5000 from Grandfather" and others from Grandmother, Aunt Bess Adams, Mme. Costantini, Louise Bates, Auntie Stevens, Aunt Marguerite, and Louise Gaylord. A certificate from the British Chaplain at Florence records his christening by the Rev. A.A. Knollys on 29 April 1907.
      Other people photographed include Kathleen Sheriff, Mrs [or Miss] Boyd and Ella and Isabella O'Connor.
      There are two prints of HA as a Toreador and WA as Pierrot and a clipping reporting the costume ball held on January 9 1909 for children at the Villa Christina, the home of Mr Henry Labouchere, mentioning the Acton children as among the guests.
      WA and HA are also photographed in the gardens of Villa La Pietra 18 February 1912 as 'Turks' for the Braggiotti children's fancy-dress ball.
      There are prints of his schools: Wixenford in Wokingham, annotated Sept 1915 to Easter 1916, and Chateau de Lancy, Sept 1916-July 1917.
      There are dried flowers "from Grandfather's casket, March 12th 1910, Chicago".
      Some of the prints are duplicates or in the same series as those in I.C.1., I.C.2. and in I.D.1.The photos are all pasted onto the pages and annotated by HMA, but put together with less care than those in HA's baby book, and often there are photos in the same series not on consecutive pages.
  - Subseries C: Albums of Places and Art work
    - 1. Veronese frescoes at Villa Maser, taken by C. Naya, 1873; cuid289 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      This is a large album of 59 loose mounted photographs captioned: "affreschi di Paolo Veronese a Maser presso Treviso (N. 1530 + 1588) - Riproduzione tratta dall'originale di C. Naya fotografo di S.M. il Re d'Italia - Venezia Agosto 187".These are the famous frescoes by Paolo Veronese (1530-1588) at Villa Maser, near Treviso, and the photographer, C. Naya, was a very well-known professional photographer of Venezia, photographer to the King of Italy. They are dated August 1873. The captions are all identical so that the subject matter of the fresco and the room have not been specified.
      The album and mounts are in poor condition, with signs of mould and bevelling.
      Villa Maser was acquired by Count Giuseppe Volpi in 1935 for his daughter Marina, who in 1945 married Conte Enrico Luling Buschetti. Her sister was Anna Maria Luling (Cicogna). Volpi became governor of Tripoli. HA visited the family both at Maser and in Tripoli, so this album may have been given to him (or bought by him) because of his connections with Maser.
    - 2. 'Italia' circa 1870, cuid290 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      A large, handsomely bound album entitled on the outside cover 'Italia', and probably dating from the 1870s. Professional photos, pasted on to the pages, mostly with captions incorporated. Includes some photos by the important Italian photographer G. Sommer of Napoli (and also, probably, some by Alinari). 96 prints.
      Places include: Genova (the cemetery - Camposanto - with details of the tombs), Pisa, Napoli, Vesuvio (with the funicular), Pompeii, Tivoli, Roma (including views of the Forum and famous sculptures in the Musei Vaticani and Musei Capitolini), Firenze (exteriors including views of San Miniato before the Viale dei Colle was built in 1865-70, and Piazzale Michelangelo just built (1875), and some artwork), Milano (exteriors, some art work, and the cemetery).
    - 3. Album belonging to Hortense Mitchell, September, ca. 1888; cuid291 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      A large leather-bound album inscribed on the inside cover "Hortense Lanore Mitchell Sept. 1888".
      Professional photos, pasted on to the pages, mostly with captions incorporated, but some annotated by hand. 116 prints.
      Prints of places (mostly exteriors) but also some interiors and a few art works. Places include GB: Scotland, York, Warwick, Stratford on Avon, London (including interiors of Westminster Abbey), Paris, Fontainebleau, Brussels, Antwerp, Cologne, and Heidelberg.
    - 4. Album belonging to Hortense Mitchell September, 1890; cuid292 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      A large leather-bound album made in Chicago inscribed on the inside cover: "Hortense Lanore Mitchell Sept 1890".
      The binding is identical to III.C.7., III.C.8., and II.C.9., and it bears no. 20 on the spine.
      Professional photos, pasted on to the pages, mostly with captions incorporated, but some annotated by hand. 100 prints.
      Some are Brogi and perhaps Alinari photos, and there are a conspicuous number by the important Italian photographer G. Sommer of Napoli, including mountain scenes. Places (mostly exteriors) but also interiors and statues include: Britain (Chatsworth, Canterbury, Cambridge, Oxford) France (Paris, Petit Trianon, St Cloud), Geneva, Chamounix, Mt Blanc, Lucerne, the Matterhorn, Berne, Lago Maggiore (Isola Bella), Milano, Innsbruck, St Petersburg.
    - 5. Album belonging to Marguerite Mitchell, 1891; cuid293 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      A small leather-bound album made in London inscribed on the inside cover "Marguerite Mitchell 1891". (Marguerite, later Mrs Andrew Sheriff, was Hortense Mitchell Acton's sister).Behind each photo, which is only half pasted onto the page, the subject is annotated on the page, and also given a number. It contains professional photos of sculpture from the Assyrian and classical period to the Renaissance and neoclassical period. 70 prints.
    - 6. Album belonging to Marguerite Mitchell, 1891; cuid294 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      A small album made in London (which matches no. III.C.5) inscribed: "Marguerite Mitchell 1891". Behind each photo, which is only half-pasted onto the page, the subject is annotated on the page, and also given a number. It contains professional photographs of places including: Egyptian temples and reliefs, Luxor, Palmyra, Baalbek, Delhi, Athens, Roma (some of these are Alinari photos), Pompeii (some photos by G. Sommer, Napoli), Ravenna, Constantinople, the Alhambra, India (Benares, Delhi), castles in Germany (including Heidelburg), Amiens, Strasbourg, Cologne, Nurenburg, Berlin, Versailles, Rheims, and GB: London, Windsor, Canterbury, the cathedrals of Salisbury, Wells and Norwich, and Melrose Abbey.
      Towards the end of the album there are some blank pages then photographs of sculpture on the last pages. 161 prints.
    - 7. Album made in Chicago, 1892; cuid295 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      A large leather-bound album bearing the number 19 on the spine, made in Chicago in 1892 (the binding is identical to III.C.8. and III.C.9. The large professional photos, some of them annotated, are pasted on to the page. Some of them are by G. Sommer of Napoli. They are of exteriors in Europe, including Frankfurt, Munich, Bern, Budapest, Berlin, Vienna, Nurenburg, and Marseilles. There are also genre scenes of Algerian women and musicians. 56 prints.
    - 8. Album made in Chicago, ca. 1892; cuid296 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      A large leather-bound album bearing the number 19 on the spine, made in Chicago, but undated, probably around 1892 (the binding is identical to III.C.7. and III.C.9. The professional photos are pasted on to the page without annotations, but some have captions incorporated into the photo on the recto. The subjects are works of art in various museums including the Louvre, Versailles, and Luxembourg, and they range in date from Guido Reni to Amy Scheffer. 92 prints.
    - 9. Album made in Chicago, ca. 1892; cuid297 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      A large leather-bound album bearing the number 19 on the spine, probably made in Chicago and dating from around 1892 (the binding is identical to III.C.7. and III.C.8. The professional photos are pasted on to the page, some with captions incorporated, and others annotated. Some of them are Brogi prints. The subjects are places (mostly exteriors but a few interiors), statues, gardens, and artwork. Places include Dresden (with some market scenes), Meissen, Berlin, Potsdam, Frankfurt, and the artwork is in the Hermitage, St Petersburg and in the Brera, Milano. The last pages have sentimental genre scenes by contemporary painters. 70 prints.
    - 10. Album belonging to Harold Acton, 1911; cuid298 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      A small bound album inscribed on the inside cover: "Harold Acton, 1911". Professional photographs of works of art, all of them annotated with the name of the artist and the title of the work, and sometimes its location. These include famous works from the 14th century up to the late 19th century many of them in Firenze, Roma and the rest of Italy as well as museums all over Europe. In the middle of the book is a postcard photo of 8 children who may be the Braggiotti who were childhood friends of HA's (printed on the recto: "Teatro Niccolini, recita di benificenza, 3 aprile 1913)". (Niccolini Theatre (in Florence): charity performance, 3 April 1913. 210 prints.
    - 11. Album belonging to William Acton, 1912; cuid299 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      A small bound album which matches album III.C.10, inscribed on the inside cover "William Acton, 1912". Professional photographs of contemporary or late 19th-century paintings, all of them annotated. Many of the artists are nowadays little known. 95 prints.
    - 12 Album (empty) of Guy Mitchell's Villa Passerini, 1908; cuid300 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      A very fine leather-bound album, with HMA's bookplate, and annotated on the inside cover: "Villa Passerini - owned by Guy Mitchell and restored". The villa was bought by Guy in 1908 and sold in 1929.
      This is now an empty album (with photocopies inserted into some of the pages
    - 13. Album (empty) of Villa La Pietra Gardens, around, 1930; cuid301 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      A small album labelled on the outside cover "Il Giardino La Pietra". But now empty (the photographs formerly here were apparently taken by Gebruder [or Gebrucher] Mertens, Zurich c. 1930.
- Series IV: Works of Art
  - Subseries A, cuid50
    This series is currently being processed and is unavailable for consultation.
  - Subseries B: Art objects (with locations)
    - 1 Paintings, drawings and prints, i. Italy
      - Bergamo, S. Grata Borramini, P.V., Macabre scenes (exhibited 1922), undated; cuid3164 (Box 14, Folder 1)
        Photo Alinari 45325.
      - Caso (Spoleto), S. Cristina (present whereabouts unknown) [13th-14th century] painted Cross, undated; cuid3165 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        Photo Anderson 5952.
      - Chiusdino (Siena Sassetta), Madonna and Child (detail), undated; cuid3166 (Box 14, Folder 3)
        Photo Anderson 21801.
      - Empoli (Firenze), Ponte a Elsa, chiesa del Canneto, Neri di Bicci, Madonna and Child enthroned with four Saints, undated; cuid3167 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        Annotated on the verso Photo Reali 227.
      - Fiesole (Firenze), Duomo, [Bicci di Lorenzo], Triptych of the Madonna and Child enthroned with angels and Saints., undated; cuid3168 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        Photo Reali, ed. Brogi 7758.
      - Fiesole (Firenze), S. Ansano (now Museo Bandini, Fiesole), School of Taddeo Gaddi, Madonna and Child with four Saints, undated; cuid3169 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        Photo Reali, [Brogi] 7744.
      - Figline Valdarno (Firenze), Collegiata di Santa Maria, Master of Figline (Master of the Fogg Pietà), Madonna enthroned with Saints, undated; cuid3170 (Box 14, Folder 7)
        Annotated on the verso "Chiesa della Misericordia di Figline -Valdarno" Photo Reali 207.
      - Figline Valdarno (Firenze), Giovanni del Biondo, Madonna and Child, undated; cuid3171 (Box 14, Folder 7a.)
        Annotated on the verso "Chiesa della Misericordia di Figline - Valdarno. Giovanni del Biondo" Photo Reali 155.
      - Firenze, Galleria dell'Accademia, Pacino di Buonaguida, two details of his Albero della Vita, undated; cuid3172 (Box 14, Folder 8)
        Photo Brogi 19997. (captioned "Firenze, Antica e Moderna")
      - Firenze [Galleria dell'Accademia], [Lorenzo di Bicci], triptych of the Madonna enthroned with four Saints, undated; cuid3173 (Box 14, Folder 9)
        Photo Reali, ed. Brogi 2496. (captioned "Accademia di Belle Arti")
      - Firenze [Galleria degli Uffizi], Baciccio (Giovanni Battista Gaulli), Portrait of Cardinal Leopoldo de' Medici, undated; cuid3174 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        Photo Brogi 19007.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Bassano, Iacopo, Self portrait with his family, undated; cuid3175 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        Photo Reali, ed. Alinari P.2. 900
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Botticelli, detail of the Primavera (Flora), undated; cuid3176 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        Photo print Alinari 1460.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Boucher, Francesco, Christ Child and the young St John, undated; cuid3177 (Box 14, Folder 13)
        Photo captioned #2172.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi, Allori, Alessandro, Portrait of Bianca Cappello (fresco), undated; cuid3178 (Box 14, Folder 14)
        Photo captioned #2259. and attributed to Angiolo Bronzino.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Duccio di Buoninsegna, Maestà (formerly in Santa Maria Novella), undated; cuid3179 (Box 14, Folder 15)
        Photo print Alinari 4020. Captioned Santa Maria Novella and attributed to Cimabue.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi [Giorgione], a knight with his page ('Gattamelata'), undated; cuid3180 (Box 14, Folder 16)
        Photo Brogi 2187.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Longhi, Pietro, Portrait of a Venetian lady, undated; cuid3181 (Box 14, Folder 17)
        Photo Alinari 31156.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Lorenzo Monaco, details of the predella of the Coronation of the Virgin, undated; cuid3182 (Box 14, Folder 18)
        Annotated on the verso Photo Reali 75., 76., 77., 78.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Perugino, Madonna enthroned with two Saints, undated; cuid3183 (Box 14, Folder 19)
        Photo print Alinari 1047.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi, Antonio del Pollaiolo, Portrait of a man, undated; cuid3184 (Box 14, Folder 20)
        Annotated on the verso "Presumed portrait of Orsino di Jacopo Lanfredi, b. about 1442 died after 1475. Uffizi Gallery no. 30bis. - variously ascribed to Antonio and Piero del Pollaiuolo - but the latter by authorities - Bode, [Reinach], Cruttwell etc." Photo Reali, ed. Alinari P.2. 894
      - Galleria degli Uffizi, Firenze Salvator Rosa, Self portrait, undated; cuid3185 (Box 14, Folder 21)
        Photo Reali, ed. Brogi 2644.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Tiziano, Madonna and Child with the young St John and St Anthony Abbot (detail), undated; cuid3186 (Box 14, Folder 22)
        Photo print by Alinari 1071.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Vasari, Giorgio, Portrait of Alessandro de' Medici, undated; cuid3187 (Box 14, Folder 23)
        Photo Brogi 17696.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Verrocchio, details of the Baptism of Christ, undated; cuid3188 (Box 14, Folder 24)
        #1. Photo Reali, ed. Alinari P.2.1660.
        #2. Photo captioned 2275., and on the recto stamped Giuseppina Novelli, Firenze.
      - [Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi] [12th century] Madonna and Child, undated; cuid3189 (Box 14, Folder 25)
        Photo Alinari 30502.
      - [Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi] Byzantine master, Madonna and Child with angels, undated; cuid3190 (Box 14, Folder 26)
        Photo Alinari 30501.
      - [Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi] [12th century master], details of a Passion cycle (the Way to Calvary and the Maries at the tomb), undated; cuid3191 (Box 14, Folder 27)
        Photo Brogi 19987. and 19984.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi [14th-15th century master], Madonna of Humility (with angels), undated; cuid3192 (Box 14, Folder 28)
        Photo Reali 6684.
      - [Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi] [14th-15th century master], Madonna and Child with two Saints, undated; cuid3193 (Box 14, Folder 29)
        Photo Reali 224., captioned "Segreteria della Galleria Antica e Moderna".
      - Firenze, formerly Museo di Firenze com'era Utens, Giusto, lunette of the Medici Villa La Peggio (Lapeggio), undated; cuid3194 (Box 14, Folder 30)
        Photo of the Soprintendenza di Firenze, 6811. All 14 lunettes of the Medici Villas by Utens have been exhibited since 2013 at the Villa della Petraia, Florence.
      - Firenze, [Museo Nazionale del Bargello] [15th century master], detail of a Madonna and Child, undated; cuid3195 (Box 14, Folder 31)
        Photo Reali 183. Annotated on the verso with the location.
      - Firenze, Museo di San Marco Fra' Angelico, Madonna and Child (Tabernacolo dei Linaiuoli), undated; cuid3196 (Box 14, Folder 32)
        Alinari photo print 647., captioned Galleria degli Uffizi.
      - Firenze, Palazzo Pitti Sustermans (Suttermans), Giusto, undated; cuid3197 (Box 14, Folder 33)
        1. Holy Family. Photo Reali, ed. Brogi 7934.
        2. detail of the portrait of the son of Frederick III, King of Denmark. Photo Brogi 7933.
      - Firenze, Palazzo Vecchio Stradano, details of ceilings in the Quartiere di Eleonora, undated; cuid3198 (Box 14, Folder 34)
        Photos Alinari 16985. and 16988.
      - Firenze, Palazzo Vecchio Vasari, Giorgio, detail of the walls of the Sala di Giovanni delle Bande Nere in the Quartiere di Leone X, with a portrait of Caterina Sforza, undated; cuid3199 (Box 14, Folder 35)
        Photo Alinari 16974.
      - Firenze, Galleria degli Uffizi Giotto, Dossal with Madonna and Child and four Saints (Badia polyptych), undated; cuid3200 (Box 14, Folder 36)
        Photo Reali 175. Annotated on the verso 'Firenze, chiesa di S. Croce, Ignoto del sec. XV or scuola di Giotto.".
      - Firenze, San Giorgio sulla costa (now Museo Diocesano d'Arte Sacra, Santo Stefano al Ponte) Giotto, Madonna and Child enthroned, undated; cuid3201 (Box 14, Folder 37)
        Photo Brogi 19959.
      - Firenze, S. Leonardo in Arcetri Lorenzo di Niccolò (or Lorenzo di Bicci), Madonna and Child, undated; cuid3202 (Box 14, Folder 38)
        Annotated on the verso. Photo Reali 121.
      - [Firenze, S. Lucia dei Magnoli] Lippi, Filippo, two panels of an Annunciation, undated; cuid3203 (Box 14, Folder 39)
        Annotated on the verso. Photo Reali 103.
      - Firenze [S. Maria del Carmine] [15th century master], Polyptych with the Madonna and Child enthroned with angels and four saints, undated; cuid3204 (Box 14, Folder 40)
        Annotated on the verso. Photo Reali 153.
      - [13th-century master] St Margaret and scenes from her life undated [13th-14th-century master] Madonna and Child enthroned, cuid3205 (Box 14, Folder 41)
        1.-3.[13th century master].
      - St Margaret and scenes from her life, and details, undated; cuid3206 (Box 41, Folder Missing Value)
      - Firenze, S. Niccolò sopr'Arno Bicci di Lorenzo, Madonna and Child with six saints, undated; cuid3207 (Box 14, Folder 42)
        Annotated on the verso. Photo Reali 44.
      - Firenze, S. Spirito Raffaellino del Garbo, Trinity and Saints, undated; cuid3208 (Box 14, Folder 43)
      - Firenze, S. Spirito Maso di Banco, Mary Magdalen, S. Andrea, S. Julian, and S. Catherine of Alexandria, undated; cuid3209 (Box 14, Folder 44)
        Annotated on the verso "Ignoto, sec. XV". Photo Reali 174.
      - Firenze, [chiesa di Soffiano], (now Signano, Scandicci, S. Giusto) Daddi, Bernardo, Madonna enthroned with four Saints, undated; cuid3210 (Box 14, Folder 45)
        Annotated on the verso. Photo Reali 89.
      - Firenze, [tabernacle in Via Michelangiolo] Gaddi, Agnolo, Madonna and Child with two Saints and a donor, undated; cuid3211 (Box 14, Folder 46)
        Photo Alinari 31053.
      - [Grosseto, Duomo] Byzantine master, Last Judgement, undated; cuid3212 (Box 15, Folder 1)
        Annotated on the verso and Numbered 2890. Photo Lombardi, Siena.
      - Impruneta (Firenze), Collegiata [13th-14th century master], Madonna and Child, undated; cuid3213 (Box 15, Folder 2)
        Photo Brogi 7771.
      - Lucca, Pinacoteca Pontormo, Portrait of a boy, undated; cuid3214 (Box 15, Folder 3)
        Photo Brogi 19639.
      - Massa Marittima (Grosseto), Duomo Follower of Duccio di Buoninsegna [or Simone Martini], Madonna 'delle Grazie', undated; cuid3215 (Box 15, Folder 4)